# Titouan Renard,

# Master student in Robotics with a minor in Data Science

© (+41) 79 944 61 65

#### 図 titouan.renard@epfl.ch 命 github.com/RenardDesNeiges

© Rue de la paix 9, 1020 Renens, Switzerland

I am student at EPFL currently pursuing a Master of Sciences in Robotics with a minor in Data Science. I am interested in control theory, machine learning and their applications to robotic systems. I also have some experience in student associations and am proficient in French and English.

#### **Education**

Ongoing <b>Master in Robotics with a Minor in Data Science</b> , Lausanne, Switzerland EPFL, STI and IC faculties	2020-Present
<b>Bachelor in Microengineering</b> , Lausanne, Switzerland EPFL, STI faculty	2020
<b>Bilingual Maturité</b> , Neuchâtel, Switzerland French-English bilingual high-school, Lycée Denis de Rougemont, Physics and Applied Math	2016

# **Experience**

•	
<b>Copresident</b> , Unipoly (student's association for sustainabily at EPFL). Responsible for an association of approximately 300 membres with a 20'000 CHF annual budget	2021-2022
<b>Student-Assistant at EPFL</b> , for the courses "Physique Générale 1" (Newtonian Mechanics), "Microinformatique" (basics of embedded systems programming for Microengineering students), Basics of Robotics and Material Sciences Practicals	2018-Present
<b>Responsable Politique</b> , member of the direction comity of Unipoly, responsible for interactions with stakeholders and EPFL's direction on matters of sustainabily on campus. Public relations experience, some experience with media and press releases.	2020-2021
Responsible of Events for the 2020 sustainabily week on EPFL campus, Unipoly,	2020

Management and coordination of about 30 events on EPFL and UNILs campuses.	
Summer Internship, Birorobotics Lab EPFL, at the Biorobotics Laboratory at EPFL,	2018
implementation of a simple vision-based localization system using C++ and OpenCV.	

# **European Youth Parliament**, Switzerland English language public speaking experience. 2015-2016

## **Skills**

**Programming**, in C, C++, Javascript, Matlab, Python and Scala. Experience with OpenCV, Scipy, CasAdi, Tensorflow and Pytorch, comfortable with Unix systems and git.

**Math and Applied Math**, Probabilities, Linear Algebra, Calculus, Dynamic System Theory and Control Theory, Signal Processing, Algorithmic Design and Analysis. Strong abstraction capacity, ability to mathematically forumlate a concrete problem.

**Languages**, French (native proficiency), English (full proficiency), German (high-school level, B2)

**Soft Skills**, public speaking, writing and team management learned in the context student associations

### **Relevant Courses**

Course	Grade
Model Predictive Control (ME-425)	5.75/6
Algorithms (CS-250)	5.5/6
Advanced Algorithms (CS-450)	6/6
Artifical Neural Networks (CS-456)	5.75/6
Aerial Robotics (MICRO-502)	5/6
Computer Vision (CS-442)	5.5/6
Titouan Renard's Résumé October 2021. ⊠ titouan renard@enfl.ch	Page 1 / 2